techcu.com 2005-12-20

# Tech CU - resources - about_tech_cu - privacy - Privacy Policy

.

Effective Date: 7/21/2004  

Whether you are a current or former Technology Credit Union member, or just visiting us online, we understand and respect your right to privacy. We are committed to protecting all of your personally identifiable information that you have entrusted to us.  
Privacy of Member and Former Member Information 

_What this policy covers:_  
This policy covers "non-public personal information." This means personally identifiable information that Technology Credit Union and our affiliate, Tech CU Financial Services, Inc. (including the Car Store), obtain about you in the course of providing services to you, our members and former members. It does not cover information that we or other entities obtain from public sources such as telephone directories or county real property records. It does not cover information that is not identified with any individual member or former member, such as a statement that a specified number of our members have auto loans with us, or a statement that the average combined account balance of our membership is a specified dollar amount. In this policy, the term "member" refers to both current and former members.

Topics   

  * [Specific examples of third parties to whom we disclose information](http://www.techcu.com/templates/content_ln.aspx?NRMODE=Published&NRORIGINALURL=%2fResources%2fAbout_Tech_CU%2fPrivacy%2fprivacy%2ehtml&NRNODEGUID=%7bC172AA5E-F308-410F-BD48-B919B64B1DA9%7d&NRCACHEHINT=NoModifyGuest#examples)
  * [Our maintenance of the privacy and security of your information](http://www.techcu.com/templates/content_ln.aspx?NRMODE=Published&NRORIGINALURL=%2fResources%2fAbout_Tech_CU%2fPrivacy%2fprivacy%2ehtml&NRNODEGUID=%7bC172AA5E-F308-410F-BD48-B919B64B1DA9%7d&NRCACHEHINT=NoModifyGuest#maintenance)

**Where we collect information about you.**  
Sources from which we collect information about you include:

  * Your applications for our products and services; 
  * Consumer reporting agencies such as credit bureaus and agencies that report checking account abuses; 
  * Third parties we ask to verify information you have provided on your applications for our services, such as current and past employers or other creditors; 
  * Third parties with whom we have arrangements to provide services to you, such as financial institutions whose ATM's you use, merchants who accept your Credit Union credit and/or debit card, mortgage lenders, or vehicle dealers. 
  * Our affiliates where we collect information such as account balances, payment history, parties to transactions, and credit card usage. 

**Selling Information **

We do not sell any of your personal information to other parties or direct marketers. However, under certain circumstances we do share selected information about you as described in the next paragraph. 

**Third parties to whom we may disclose information about you**

We may disclose to third parties any information that we collect about you, including but not limited to your name, your address, your social security number, your date of birth, your transaction history with us, your assets and your income.

**We may disclose information about you under the following general circumstances:**

  * To the extent necessary to provide services that you request; 
  * To the extent necessary to conduct our business; 
  * To our internal and external auditors, to our legal advisors, to our insurers, and to our regulatory agencies such as the California Department of Financial Institutions or the National Credit Union Administration; 
  * If we are required to do so by law, such as when we receive a court order, levy, subpoena, or other validly issued legal process; 
  * If you give us written permission. 

The Credit Union or Tech CU Financial Services, Inc. (including the Car Store) may disclose information about you to third parties that sell their own products or services. Although we do not guarantee the products or services of any third party, we select third parties to which we give information about you carefully, and believe the products or services they offer may be of interest to you. Examples of third parties to whom we may give information about members include financial planners, Financial Advisors, and companies that sell various types of insurance.

We will generally disclose only your name, address and telephone number. We may give lists of members who fall within certain categories, such as a range of ages, income, account balances, or home ownership, so that third parties can target their promotions to members who are likely to be interested in and qualified for the offered products or services. 

We never give your specific financial information, account numbers, personal identification (social security number, driver's license, etc), or PINs to third parties selling their own products or services to you. You can prohibit us from disclosing information about you to third parties selling their own products and services, and prohibit the Credit Union and Tech CU Financial Services, Inc. (including the Car Store) from exchanging information (other than transaction and experience information) about you, by following the instructions in the Opting Out section below. Once a third party has information about you, however, they may continue to contact you. You should contact the third party directly if you wish to be excluded from their contact lists.

**Specific examples of third parties to whom we may disclose information**

Following are some specific examples of the types of third parties to whom we may disclose information to::

  * Credit bureaus; 
  * Third party vendors that assist us with providing or marketing member services, such as check printers, mortgage lenders, mail houses, plastic card processors, credit life and disability insurance providers, collateral appraisers, vehicle dealers participating in our dealer loan programs, bill payment service providers, credit bureaus, eFunds (Qualifile), and other electronic service providers upon your (member) initiated request; 
  * Third parties with whom we have joint marketing arrangements; 
  * Third parties who are involved in your transactions, such as the Federal Reserve and other financial institutions that process your checks, automated clearinghouse (ACH) transactions and ATM transactions; 
  * Third parties whose services are necessary to meet our business needs, such as the Department of Motor Vehicles, companies that insure collateral you have pledged as security for Credit Union loans, and debt collectors. 

**Do third party vendors share or sell information about me?**

When we share information with a third party , we take every precaution to ensure that your information is protected. All third parties that offer their services or products to a Technology Credit Union member must agree in writing to our privacy standards.

**Our maintenance of the privacy and security of your information:**

We restrict access to non-public personal information about you to persons who have a need to know the information to provide products and services for you or to meet our reasonable business needs. Credit Union staff, management and volunteers are trained to keep member information strictly confidential. If we release information about you to third parties, they must sign agreements to keep your information confidential unless certain conditions are met. For example, they are permitted to disclose information about you if necessary to provide products and services to you, if ordered to do so by a court, if necessary to conduct their own business, or if you give them permission. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulation to guard your non-public personal information.

**Our right to change this policy:**

This policy is effective July 1, 2001. We can change this policy by notifying you in writing. If a new policy will be subject to opt-out rights, we will give you at least 30 days advance notice before the new policy goes into effect, and we will disclose means by which you can opt out of disclosure of non-public personal information.

**Opting Out:**

If you do not want us to give information about you to third parties who are selling their own products or services, you can opt out at any time by:

  * Calling (408) 451-9111 or (800) 553-0880 (outside the 408 area code) 
  * Completing a form at any [Technology Credit Union branch](http://www.techcu.com/resources/locations/branches.htm "Technology Credit Union Branch"). 
  * Completing the following [secure online form](https://webbranch.techcu.com/onlineapps/optout.asp "secure online form")

It generally takes 1 week to implement an opt-out request on our computer system. If you later decide you no longer want to opt out, you can let us know by calling, writing, or by sending an email to us.

**Can I opt out from receiving disclosures?**

You cannot opt out of disclosure of information about you as described in this section.

**Personal Information Accuracy**

We make every effort to ensure the accuracy of your personal information you provide us. If you identify an error, or need to change or update your current information, please notify us so we can promptly update our records. You may report any errors by:

  * Calling (408) 451-9111 or (800) 553-0880 (outside the 408 area code) 
  * Sending us a secure email through [Online Banking](https://webbranch.techcu.com/ "Online Banking")
